<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<set>
	<question>
		<statement>In Mr. Mehta's family, there are one grandfather, one grandmother, two fathers, two mothers, one father-in-law, one mother-in-law, four children, three grandchildren, one brother, two sisters, two sons, two daughters and one daughter-in-law.  How many members are there in Mr. Mehta's family? Give minimal possible answer.
		</statement>
		<answer>7</answer>
		<hint>Each person in the world has so many roles to play.</hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement>The king of the universe has decided to play a game. To start, he selects 1 person. He then flips two fair coins - if they both come up heads, the person gets a free pizza and the game is over. For any other result, he sends the person home and selects 2 new people, where he does the same 2-coin flip to decide if they each get a pizza. If they don’t, he picks 4 people at random, then 8, and so on, doubling each round. If you are selected but don’t win, you can’t be selected again – and you can assume the population is extremely large so there’s no chance of running out of contestants.You are sitting at home when you get a call – you have been selected to play the game. If the chance that you will get a free pizza is p, then 100 X p=?
		</statement>
		<answer>25</answer>
		<hint>Independence is indispensable</hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement>If 5+3=28, 9+1=810, 8+6=214, 5+4=19 then 15+11= ?
		</statement>
		<answer>426</answer>
		<hint>Subtraction +Addition</hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement>Find the next number in the sequence 23 21 24 19 26 15 28 11 30 7 36 5?</statement>
		<answer>42</answer>
		<hint>I think prime numbers are like life - Mark Huddon</hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement> Once upon a time, there was an old lady with a lot of eggs. She went to sell her vast quantity of eggs at the local market.
When a small boy asked how many she had, she replied:
Son, I can't count past 100 but I know that.
If you divide the number of eggs by 2 there will be one egg left.
If you divide the number of eggs by 3 there will be one egg left.
If you divide the number of eggs by 4 there will be one egg left.
If you divide the number of eggs by 5 there will be one egg left.
If you divide the number of eggs by 6 there will be one egg left.
If you divide the number of eggs by 7 there will be one egg left
If you divide the number of eggs by 8 there will be one egg left.
If you divide the number of eggs by 9 there will be one egg left.
If you divide the number of eggs by 10 there will be one egg left.
Finally, if you divide the Number of eggs by 11 there will be NO EGGS left.How many eggs did the old lady have?
		</statement>
		<answer>25201</answer>
		<hint>Remember your school days when you used to find LCM (least common multiple of a set of numbers.</hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement>Here is a sequence of numbers: 1 11 21 1211 111221 312211 It seems to be a strange sequence, but yet there is a system behind it... What is the next term in this sequence?
		</statement>
		<answer>13112221</answer>
		<hint>There isn’t a better way to describe a number. </hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement>Four people want to pass through a tunnel; they all begin on the same side.It is dark, and they have one flashlight. Any party that crosses, either one or two people, must have the flashlight with them.The flashlight must be walked back and forth; it cannot be thrown, Bob can make it in 1 minute, Marie in 2 minutes, Gordon in 4 and Elizabeth in 5 minutes. Not more than two persons can go through the narrow tunnel at one time, and they have to move at the speed of the slower one.What is minimum time needed to cross the tunnel?
		</statement>
		<answer>12</answer>
		<hint>Don’t be greedy (always).</hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement>You are given 12 metal balls, with one being heavier than the others. What is the minimum number of weighings using a two-pan balance scale needed to guarantee identifying the heavy ball?
		</statement>
		<answer>3</answer>
		<hint>Divide the balls in three groups. Think what will be appropriate number of balls in each group.</hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement>An enemy spy has poisoned one out of 1000 barrels of wine in a king's cellar. Even a sip of the poisoned wine has potency to kill. However, the effects of the poison show only in 30 days. The king asks the royal jailor to identify the poisoned barrel within 30 days. What is the least number of prisoners the jailor must employ to identify the poisoned barrel?
		</statement>
		<answer>10</answer>
		<hint>Binary representations do wonders sometimes. </hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement>A banana plantation is located next to a desert. The plantation owner has 3000 bananas that he wants to transport to the market by camel, across a 1000 kilometer stretch of desert. The owner has only one camel, which carries a maximum of 1000 bananas at any moment in time, and the camel eats one banana every kilometer it travels. What is the largest number (not necessarily an integer) of bananas that can be delivered at the market?  
		</statement>
		<answer>533.33</answer>
		<hint>You can cache bananas in the desert.  Also, non-integer number of bananas (e.g. 223.5 bananas) can be cached.</hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement>Given a 3X3x3 cube, if you want to construct 27 units of 1x1X1 cubes, what is the minimum number of cuts needed?</statement>
		<answer>6</answer>
		<hint>No cut can reveal two or more faces!</hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement>An evil troll once captured a bunch of 1015 gnomes and told them, "Tomorrow, I will make you stand in a file, ordered by height such that a gnome can see exactly those gnomes that are shorter than him. I will place either a white cap or a black cap on each head. Then, starting from the tallest, each gnome has to declare aloud what he thinks the color of his own cap is. In the end, those who were correct will be spared; others will be eaten, silently." The gnomes set thinking and came up with a strategy. How many of them survived?
		</statement>
		<answer>1014</answer>
		<hint>PARITY is your savior.</hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement>Jack and his wife went to a party where other four married couples were present. Every person shook hands with everyone he or she was not acquainted with. When the handshaking was over, Jack asked everyone, including his own wife, how many hands they shook. To his surprise, Jack got nine different answers. How many hands did Jack's wife shake?
		</statement>
		<answer>4</answer>
		<hint>Think how many hands were shaken by the person whose partner shook 12 hands.</hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement>A man walks into a bar, orders a drink, and starts chatting with the bartender. After a while, he learns that the bartender has three children. "How old are your children?" he asks. "Well," replies the bartender, "the product of their ages is 72." The man thinks for a moment and then says, "that's not enough information." "All right," continues the bartender, "if you go outside and look at the building number posted over the door to the bar, you'll see the sum of the ages." The man steps outside, and after a few moments he reenters and declares, "Still not enough!" The bartender smiles and says, "My youngest just loves strawberry ice cream." How old are the children? List them in non-increasing order.  Separate the numbers with ‘-‘ (e.g.  7-5-5) 
		</statement>
		<answer>6-6-2</answer>
		<hint>Even after knowing the sum, the man says “Still not enough!". Think what can be the reason behind that.</hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement>There was a death on Treebark Ln. The victim was identified as Mark Oswalt, who recently was married. The police went to the crime scene and they reported the death as a suicide. 

Later that day, after the police left, a private detective, hired by the victim's friend who thought it was a murder, searched the crime scene and found a note the police missed.

It read,

"4,3: 8,1:_: 9,1: 2,1: 7,4:_: 6,1:9,3:_: 9,1: 4,3: 3,3: 3,2: !"

The detective took out his cell phone and started dialing the police to tell them about his findings. Once the detective opened the phone to dial, he immediately screamed out, "I SOLVED IT!"
What is the message in the note?
		</statement>
		<answer>itwasmywife</answer>
		<hint>Mark Oswalt used his CELL PHONE for business calls many times a day</hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement> A number of 9 digits has the following properties:   The number comprising the leftmost two digits is divisible by 2, that comprising the leftmost three digits is divisible by 3, the leftmost four by 4, the leftmost five by 5, and so on for the nine digits of the number. Each digit in the number is different i.e. no digits are repeated. The digit 0 does not occur in the number i.e. it is comprised only of the digits 1-9 in some order. Find out the number.
		</statement>
		<answer>381654729</answer>
		<hint>Trial and error!! </hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement>Justin Case and Auntie Bellum are fellow con artists who deliver coded messages to each other to communicate. Recently Auntie Bellum was put in jail for stealing a rare and expensive diamond. Only a few days after this, Justin Case sent her a friendly letter asking her how she was. On the inside of the envelope of the letter, he hid a code. Yesterday, Auntie Bellum escaped and left the envelope and the letter inside the jail cell. The police did some research and found the code on the inside of the envelope, but they haven't been able to crack it. Could you help the police find out what the message is?
	This is the code:
llwatchawtfeclocklnisksundialcirbetimersool
		</statement>
		<answer>loosebricksinleftwall</answer>
		<hint>It was a TIMED escape.</hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement img="img/chess.png">The squares of an 8×8 chessboard are mistakenly colored in blocks of two colors .You need to cut this board along some lines separating its rows and columns so that the standard 8 × 8 chessboard can be reassembled from the pieces obtained. What is the minimum number of pieces into which the board needs to be cut and how should they be reassembled?
		</statement>
		<answer>25</answer>
		<hint>Think what parts of the board do you have to cut to solve the puzzle</hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement>Five pirates have obtained 100 gold coins and have to divide up the loot. The pirates are all extremely intelligent, treacherous and selfish (especially the captain).

The captain always proposes a distribution of the loot. All pirates vote on the proposal, and if half the crew or more go "Aye", the loot is divided as proposed, as no pirate would be willing to take on the captain without superior force on their side. 

If the captain fails to obtain support  of at least half his crew (which includes himself), he faces a mutiny,  and all pirates will turn against him and make him walk the plank. The  pirates start over again with the next senior pirate as  captain. 

What is the maximum number of coins the captain can keep without risking his life?</statement>
	    <answer>98</answer>
		<hint>First consider the case for a single pirate, and move up</hint>
	</question>
	<question>
		<statement>What does this message say?

G T Y O R J O T E O U I A B G T</statement>
		<answer>greatjobyougotit</answer>
		<hint>Count the letters and try splitting the letters up into groups and rearrange them vertically.</hint>
	</question>
</set>
